const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {}
let acceptingAnswers = true
let score = 0
let questionCounter = 0
let availableQuestions = []

let questions = [

    {
        question:
        "1. An IP router normally uses which of the following pieces of information to forward an IP packet?",
        choice1: 'The destination IP address only',
        choice2: 'The source and destination IP address',
        choice3: 'The destination IP address and the destination TCP port',
        choice4: 'The destination IP address, the TTL, and the ToS',
        answer: 1,
        },							
        {						
        question: 
        "2. The two main categories of routing protocols are IGP and ______.",
        choice1: 'OSPF',
        choice2: 'Link state',
        choice3: 'BGP',
        choice4: 'EGP',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question: 
        "3. Which of the following is not a characteristic of an IGP?",
        choice1: 'It is intended for networks under a common administrative control.',
        choice2: 'It is used between ASes.',
        choice3: 'There are not as many policy enforcement features as an EGP.',
        choice4: 'It includes distance vector and link state protocols.',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "4. A router can run multiple routing protocols that each have their own table of routing information. A router selects the best route for each destination from all routing sources and puts them in the ______.",
        choice1: 'Routing Link Database',
        choice2: 'Routing Information Base',
        choice3: 'Routing Table',
        choice4: 'ARP Table',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "5. Which of the following pairings is not correct?",
        choice1: 'EGP—BGP4',
        choice2: 'Link state—OSPF',
        choice3: 'IGP—RIP',
        choice4: 'Distance vector—IS-IS',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "6. In which situation would you be most likely to use a static default route?",
        choice1: 'In small networks',
        choice2: 'On links with only a single path to other routers',
        choice3: 'When you have older routers',
        choice4: 'On a low-bandwidth link',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "7. It is said that distance vector protocols have a longer convergence time than link state protocols. What is the most likely reason for this?",
        choice1: 'Link state protocols send less information.',
        choice2: 'Link state protocols keep track of neighbors via Hello updates.',
        choice3: 'The shortest path algorithm is much faster to calculate than the calculation performed by a distance vector protocol.',
        choice4: 'Distance vector protocols rely on updates only from neighbors.',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "8. There are many advantages of link state protocols over distance vector protocols. Which of the following is a potential advantage of distance vector?",
        choice1: 'Distance vector sends its entire routing table in updates.',
        choice2: 'Distance vector does not require extensive processing to build the routing table.',
        choice3: 'Distance vector sends updates at timed intervals.',
        choice4: 'Distance vector relies on neighbors to report routing updates.',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "9. When a link state router receives an LSP update, it uses what algorithm to calculate its routing table?",
        choice1: 'OSPF',
        choice2: 'Spanning tree',
        choice3: 'SPF',
        choice4: 'Least cost',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "10. Which of the following is most likely to be used for forwarding IP packets from a stub network?",
        choice1: 'A static route',
        choice2: 'A default route',
        choice3: 'A floating static route',
        choice4: 'OSPF with the “stub area” feature',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "11. The forwarding of packets on a router is a function of the data plane. The use of a routing protocol to build routing tables is a function of ______.",
        choice1: 'The routing plane',
        choice2: 'The control plane',
        choice3: 'The OSPF plane',
        choice4: 'The protocol plane',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "12. Link state protocols flood LSP information throughout the network to each router. These LSPs are stored in ______.",
        choice1: 'The routing table',
        choice2: 'The FIB',
        choice3: 'The routing database',
        choice4: 'The link state database',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "13. If there are multiple identical network prefixes advertised by different routing protocols, the Routing Table Manager chooses the route to place in the routing table based on ______.",
        choice1: 'It enters a route based on the lowest metric value.',
        choice2: 'It enters a route based on the highest preference value.',
        choice3: 'It enters a route based on the lowest preference value.',
        choice4: 'It enters a route for each protocol in the routing table.',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "14. Using a link state protocol, which of the following best describes the view each router has of all the links in the network after all LSPs have been flooded?",
        choice1: 'Each router has a common view of the network.',
        choice2: 'Each router has a unique view of the network based on its location.',
        choice3: 'Each router knows about only those LSPs originated from its neighbors.',
        choice4: 'Each router knows about all LSPs but uses only LSPs from its neighbors to construct its view.',
        answer: 1,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "15. Which of the following is the most accurate explanation of the information a distance vector routing protocol sends to neighboring routers?",
        choice1: 'It sends Hello updates.',
        choice2: 'It sends its entire routing table.',
        choice3: 'It floods LSPs.',
        choice4: 'It sends its entire routing table and its neighbors’ routing tables.',
        answer: 2,
	
        }
    
]

const SCORE_POINTS = 1
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 20

startGame = () => {
    questionCounter = 0
    score = 0
    availableQuestions = [...questions]
    getNewQuestion()
}

getNewQuestion = () => {
    if(availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
        localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score)

        return window.location.assign('/end.html')
    }

    questionCounter++
    progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`
    progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter/MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`
    
    const questionsIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestions.length)
    currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionsIndex]
    question.innerText = currentQuestion.question

    choices.forEach(choice => {
        const number = choice.dataset['number']
        choice.innerText = currentQuestion['choice' + number]
    })

    availableQuestions.splice(questionsIndex, 1)

    acceptingAnswers = true
}

choices.forEach(choice => {
    choice.addEventListener('click', e => {
        if(!acceptingAnswers) return

        acceptingAnswers = false
        const selectedChoice = e.target
        const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset['number']

        let classToApply = selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect'

        if(classToApply === 'correct') {
            incrementScore(SCORE_POINTS)
        }

        selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply)

        setTimeout(() => {
            selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply)
            getNewQuestion()

        }, 1000)
    })
})

incrementScore = num => {
    score +=num
    scoreText.innerText = score
}

startGame()